SPARSH SAXENA

Address: Agra (U.P.), INDIA || Phone number: 9068393605 || Mail: sparshsaxena9654@gmail.com || Github:-github.com/Sparsh55

Profile Summary:-

Result Driven, Highly motivated Full stack developer having a 2.5 years of progressive experience with strong Knowledge of front-end technologies as well as backend technologies, testing tools, automation test and continuous integration in agile work environment.

<u>Personal portfolio: - https://personal-portfolio-r2t6.onrender.com/</u> (Best recommended for web view)

Skill Set/Strength & Expertise:-

Tech Stack:

- ❖ Programming languages Java oops | Java core | Vanila Js | Fundamentals of Python.
- Problem solving Data structures and algo using Java.
- ❖ Frontend Html | Css | React.js.
- ❖ Backend Node.js | Express.js.
- ❖ Database Sql | Moongoose with mongodb.
- ❖ Automation Selenium | Jenkins.
- Version control Git
- Cloud AWS(Ec2,lam,Vpc).

Soft Skills: Good communication and observational skill. • Ability to recognize the value and responsibility of working in a team. • Proactive approach in adaptability to change & learning attitude. • Excellent interpersonal skills with the ability to motivate and build a cohesive team. • Self-motivated and self-controlled.

Work Experience

Junior Software Developer |
Speroware Technologies Pvt Ltd |

2021-Present

Bengaluru, Karnataka, INDIA

Job Description:

- Experience in developing and maintaining web applications using MERN Stack (MongoDB. Express.js. React.js, Node.js)
- Proficient in frontend technologies such as HTML, CSS. And JavaScript
- Strong knowledge of database design, implementation, and optimization using MongoDB
- Experience in designing and developing RESTful APIs using Node.js and Express.js
- Proficient in React.js for building user interfaces and state management
- Ability to debug and resolve issues in existing codebase
- Automate manual test scripts of a desktop based application named Assay Analyzer using python, selenium and Winapdriver.
- Implement Pytest (Unit testing framework) with POM(page object model) approach using Dev azure and Jenkins for integration purposes.
- Ci/Cd integration using Jenkins
- Deployment on aws Ec2
- Did functional, nonfunctional and regression testing on agile environment.
- Implement TestRail and Maven for build execution.

Not working due to regular btech pursuing |

2018-2021

Diploma Engineer Trainee | VolvoEicher Commercial Vehicles Pvt Ltd | Job Description:

2016-2017 Indore, MP,INDIA

• Worked as a diploma engineer trainee before pursuing Btech at PPC (Production planning and control).

- Managing rollout plan related data and reports.
- Coordination with materials team for better planning.
- Basic SAP movements.

Projects

IMDB Clone | 2023

Description:

- ❖ Mini IMDB clone where you can search movies/webseries their cast & crew , rating etc.
- **❖ Tech Stack -** html,css,vanila JS.
- https://github.com/Sparsh55/IMDb-Clone

Personal Portfolio | 2023

Description:

- ❖ A complete web developer portfolio showcasing all work with attached deploy links to each project and journey.
- **❖ Tech Stack -** html,css,vanila JS.
- https://personal-portfolio-r2t6.onrender.com/ (Best recommended for web view)

Easily-App | 2023

Description:

- ❖ A comprehensive web app where you can post and apply for a job.
- **Tech Stack -** ejs,nodejs,express,jwt,express-sessions & cookies, nodemailer,bcrypt.
- https://github.com/Sparsh55/easily-mvc-main

Chatter-App | 2023

Description:

- Dynamic and user-friendly chatting application where you can register, login and chat with your friends having a inbuilt feature of avatars.
- **Tech Stack -** Html,css.nodejs,socket-io,jwt,express,mongodb.
- https://github.com/Sparsh55/chatter-app

PostAway-api | 2023

Description:

- Complete API setup for a social media platform (api's for login,register,follow-friends,accept friend requests,cancel friend request,logout,post and comment).
- **Tech Stack** nodejs, express, moongoose with mongodb,jwt,bcrypt.
- https://github.com/Sparsh55/postway-api

See-more on https://github.com/Sparsh55

Education

Coding Ninjas Gurgaon, India
Full Stack Development (MERN Stack) Graduation Date: 3/2024

Kalinga University
Raipur, India
Bachelors of Technology (Mech) – 8.0/10.0 CGPA
Graduation Date: 1/2022

Dayalbagh Educational Institute

Agra, India

Diploma in Polytechnic (Automobile) – 8.0/10.0 CGPA

Graduation Date: 5/2016

RadhaBallabh Inter Collage Agra, India

Intermediate – 65% Graduation Date: 4/2013

RadhaBallabh Inter Collage Agra, India

HighSchool – 68% Graduation Date: 3/2011

Certification/Award

▼ Backend development:- https://certificate.codingninjas.com/view/0ff4b59aff1bf7f3

✓ Frontend development:- https://certificate.codingninjas.com/view/6c2c75dc4d8be749

✓ Data structures and algo:- https://certificate.codingninjas.com/view/1b865233d94ab551

Language /Interest/Hobbies

Hindi(Native) | | English(Full proficiency)

Getting lost in a good book | sketching | playing football | traveling lands.